## Joe Rowley

Software engineer with a passion for healthcare!

linkedin@funk.dog

### Summary

My time has been spent working in several disciplines, but I'm most interested in healthcare. As a software engineer I've built web applications (both frontend and backend), data processing tools, and worked on code for microprocessors. I really enjoy building tools that turn complicated data into something more usable, such as an API endpoint, an interactive visualization or dashboard. As a hardware engineer I've designed a few PCBs. I've also worked extensively in teams, at times taking roles in leadership.

In my free time, I enjoy trail running, reading, and listening to music.

## Experience

#### Software Engineer, Integration Lead

February 2018 - June 2018 (5 months)

- I worked on IE8 compatible modern full stack web applications with unit tests. (Node, ES6, React, Mocha, Postgres, Mongo)
- I developed a serverless idempotent data ingestion platform (AWS Lambda, AWS SAM, python2, node, AWS Aurora/Postgres)

# Full Stack Web Engineer / Generalist at Integrated Healthcare Association February 2016 - January 2018 (2 years)

I'm was one of 3 FTE engineer here, so I did a lot of everything. I built web based reporting portals, and the data pipelines (validators, loaders) that support them.

Tools I used include:

- Python (Django, Pandas, Numpy)
- Postgres (Accessed via Django ORM, SQLAlchemy, Raw SQL)
- On the frontend, React, Redux, Redux Saga, Highcharts

#### Consultant at Bellus3D

August 2015 - December 2015 (5 months)

Research and Development, hardware prototyping.

Course Developer Assistant at University of California, Santa Cruz September 2014 - March 2015 (7 months)

I helped Phokion Kolaitis, the Chair of CS at UC Santa Cruz (at the time), create a new course, CMPS 185: Technical Writing And Communication In Computer Science. This involved researching related courses at other universities, developing curriculum and assignments, and creating a repository of interesting research papers and patents related to computer science.

#### Undergraduate Research Intern at UC Santa Cruz

July 2014 - March 2015 (9 months)

I served as the lead engineer, designed a prototype of an experimental camera flash with 10 individually controlled high power LEDs.

For more info check out the links below:

https://imgur.com/a/AzWaE

https://github.com/joer14/Portable\_RTI/

#### Programmer at Sana.mit.edu

February 2014 - October 2014 (9 months)

I'm was the lead software developer for the Sana Protocol Builder, a tool that allows clinicians to create medical algorithms that run on community health workers' smartphones in rural and low resource environments.

#### Guest Lecturer at Sana.mit.edu

July 2014 - July 2014 (1 month)

I presented with a group from MIT at Vellore institute of Technology in India, and a gave a few lectures about the Sana medical platform, and web application engineering to undergraduates.

#### Teaching Assistant at UC Santa Cruz

March 2014 - June 2014 (4 months)

I was teaching assistant for an undergraduate computer science course, CMPS 119: Software for Society under professor James Davis.

I wrote tests and quizzes, organized student groups, managed grades, and facilitated communication between students and project mentors from various NGOs.

#### Residential Assistant

September 2012 - June 2014 (1 year 10 months)

Provided assistance, guidance and counseling to 75 college freshman and upperclassmen. Tried to keep them from doing anything too silly/dangerous. More seriously, I provided support to students and staff alike. I learned a lot about people, communication, and conflict mediation in this position.

#### Student Ambassador

August 2013 - November 2013 (4 months)

I acted as Google's liaison to my university, educating students, staff and faculty about how to better use Google products.

#### Computer Technician

January 2013 - October 2013 (10 months)

I worked on a team that supports hundreds of computers on campus and the infrastructure that powers them. In addition, I developed an internal web application for tracking printer usage.

#### Google Chrome Academy

June 2013 - June 2013 (1 month)

Learned from industry experts about HTML5 and the latest web frameworks and technologies. Developed a multiplayer game with a group that uses voice recognition for interaction and Google+ for authentication.

#### Web Master & Strategist

June 2012 - February 2013 (9 months)

Worked with developers and project leaders to develop a strategy for online growth and development, implemented and maintained both content and code on the site.

# Intern at University of Wisconsin-Madison, Department of Computer Science June 2010 - September 2010 (4 months)

I developed software with an undergraduate student to track laptops for the UW - Police Department.

### Education

University of California, Santa Cruz

Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Computer Engineering, 2011 - 2015

University of California, Santa Cruz

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Computer Science, 2011 - 2015

Activities and Societies: Association of Computing and Machinery

#### Honors and Awards

Ira and Kate Pohl Computers and Society Award

## Joe Rowley

Software engineer with a passion for healthcare!

linkedin@funk.dog



Contact Joe on LinkedIn